One bullet can change everything
Hyena Road is a war, drama, thriller film directed by Paul Gross.
Three different men, three different worlds, three different wars – all stand at the intersection
of modern warfare – a murky world of fluid morality where all is not as it seems.
A unique and dramatic look at the Canadian Army in Afghanistan.
Pete, played by Paul Gross.
Ryan, played by Rossif Sutherland.
General Rilmen, played by Clark Johnson.
Travis, played by Allan Hawco.
Jennifer, played by Christine Horne.
Mary, played by Jennifer Pudavick.
Hyena Road is a 2015 Canadian war drama film directed, written and
produced by Paul Gross, starring Gross and Rossif Sutherland.
It was shown in the Gala Presentations section of the
2015 Toronto International Film Festival.
The film was shown on 24 September 2015, at the Calgary Film
Festival, before a general release on 9 October.
It won three Canadian Screen Awards.
The film is based on the true story of "Route Hyena" (formerly named Route Fosters) which was built by Task Force Kandahar between
2008–2011 during the War in Afghanistan, which over various rotations involved many units across the Canadian Armed Forces.
For this English-language film, the units are shown to be from Western Canada, based on Princess
Patricia's Canadian Light Infantry, an English-language regiment stationed in Western Canada.
The tone is emotional and intense.